[music]
[Instructor] I hope you're ready.
Because we are about to get started
on Unit 4.
Now I know there are
a lot of people out there
who say that this Unit
is the toughest one
in this entire course.
But you made it through Unit 3,
and that was no walk in the park,
so I think you're ready.
In this Unit, we will program
an arcade style sumo battle,
with the Objective
of knocking waves
of increasingly numerous enemies
off of a floating island.
The Player will have to use
powerups in a desperate effort
to withstand their relentless onslaught.
If it sound dramatic,
that's because it is.
In creating this Prototype,
you will learn how to introduce
new "Gameplay Mechanics"
into your projects.
A Gameplay Mechanic is a rule
or system in your game
that ideally makes
it more interesting to play.
One new mechanic you'll learn
to program is a Powerup,
a temporary state that will
give the Player an advantage.
These are not only super fun
for the Player to use,
but can completely change
the way a game is played.
Now the user needs to decide,
should I go for the Powerup now?
Maybe I should save the Powerup.
What should I do
when I get the Powerup?
All of these new questions,
and strategies will suddenly emerge,
and make your game
way more interesting.
The other mechanic
we'll introduce is
if you defeat all the enemies
a new wave will appear
with one more enemy
than the previous wave,
Increasing the Difficulty over time.
This will also completely change the way
the game can be played because,
instead of being a static experience
that the Player can quickly master,
and become bored of,
it has limitless potential
to challenge
even the most expert Players.
These two Gameplay Mechanics,
Powerups, and "Increasing
Difficulty" go hand and hand
because as the game
increases in difficulty
you can introduce new
Powerups to match it.
This combination basically
removes all limitations
from your project development
because you can continually
up the ante
increasing one and then increasing
the other in response.
The sky's the limit here,
so lets start creating.
[music]